Guide to the School of Architecture, Yale University, Memorabilia
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Architecture, Yale University, memorabilia
1913-2010
RU 925
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18
51 boxes
39.40
The memorabilia consists of printed material, photographs, a videotape, a film, a painting, essays and proposals, a Sketchbook and slides, and a Yale 2002 Building Project T-shirt documenting the Yale School of Architecture, its faculty and alumni. Includes non-Yale memorabilia.
Yale University. School of Architecture
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 19-H (YRG 19-H), Audio-visual materials and memorabilia documenting the Yale School of Architecture.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the School of Architecture, 2002-2011.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The memorabilia consists of printed material, photographs, a videotape, a film, a painting, essays and proposals, a Sketchbook and slides, and a Yale 2002 Building Project T-shirt documenting the Yale School of Architecture, its faculty and alumni.
Souvenirs (Keepsakes); T-shirts; Videotapes; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. School of Architecture
- Design competition article and portfolio of Erwin Hauer, 1963, 2000; Accession 2001-A-184
  - Yale architecture design competition article printed in Lucite Spectrum, 1963 September (Box 1)
  - Erwin Hauer porfolio, "Sculpture", 2000 (Box 1)
- Tee-shirt from the School of Architecture's building project, 2002; Accession 2003-A-049
  - Tee-shirt from the School of Architecture's building project, 2002 (Box 1)
- Journal of Urban Design, 2002; Accession 2003-A-150
  - Journal of Urban Design, 2002 October (Box 1)
- Taiwanese architecture journals featuring articles by Li-Yu Hsu, 2002; Accession 2003-A-151
  - Taiwanese architecture journals featuring articles by Li-Yu Hsu, 2002 (Box 1)
- Journals with articles about Yale, 2002; Accession 2004-A-012
  - Journals with articles about Yale, 2002 (Box 1)
- Reminiscences of Hugh Moore (B. Arch, 1943), 2003; Accession 2004-A-120
  - Reminiscences of Hugh Moore (B. Arch, 1943), 2003 (Box 1)
- Gavin Macrae-Gibson (M. Arch, 1979) proposal for the World Trade Center site, 2003; Accession 2004-A-121
  - Gavin Macrae-Gibson (M. Arch, 1979) proposal for the World Trade Center site, 2003 (Box 1)
- Photographs of thesis jury for Arthur A. Klipfel, III, including pictures of Paul Rudolf and Phillip Johnson; sketches by Wood of Robert Venturi, Accession 2004-A-122
  - Photographs of thesis jury for Arthur A. Klipfel, III, including pictures of Paul Rudolf and Phillip Johnson; sketches by Wood of Robert Venturi., undated (Box 1)
- "American Academy in Rome Salute to David Childs" [videorecording], 2001; Accession 2004-A-124
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - "American Academy in Rome Salute to David Childs" (B.A. 1963, M. Arch 1967), 2001; 1; videotape (VHS) (Box 1)
- Memorabilia of the School of Architecture including interviews and articles of staff and faculty, 2003-2004; Accession 2004-A-172
  - Interview of Robert A.M. Stern by Stephen Kite, April 2003 (Box 1)
  - Business New Haven article concerning Dean Sakamoto, February 2004 (Box 1)
  - School of Architecture senior T-shirt, 2004 (Box 1)
- Essays and proposals by George Izenour, professor emeritus in architecture, circa 1992-1996; Accession 2005-A-007
  - Essays and proposals by George Izenour, professor emeritus in architecture, circa 1992-1996 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, 2003-2010; Accession 2010-A-094
    The materials are open for research.
    - Yale >>Tomorrow Campaign Annual Report, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - NCARB Prize 8, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Reunion Class of '72 brochure, 2009 September 17-20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Planning for Ravenswood publication of Arch 4211b Planning and Development taught by Alexander Garvin, 2010 Spring (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Yale Architecture Open House for Admitted Students program, 2010 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Symposium program: Positioning Global Systems (2 copies), 2010 April 15-16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - NEXT! Exhibition flyer for year-end student exhibit (3 copies), 2010 May (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition brochure Eero Saarinen: Shaping the Future, 2010 Feb–May (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Norton Architecture books catalog featuring a full page of Yale authors, 2010 Spring (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Report of the Task Force on the Arts Harvard (w/ email Stern/Robinson ), 2008 December (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - New York magazine featuring students from Class of 2009, 2009 June 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Event Info packet Yale Campaign, 2008 November (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Thresholds Difference 35 pub. from MIT w/ articles written by Alex Maymind and Cody Davis both M.Arch 09, Anne Marie Armstrong M. Arch 2010 and Elizabeth Bishop M.E.D. 08, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Commencement brochures with insert of winners; fan and University program and Honorary degrees, 2010 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Commencement brochures with insert of winners; University program and Honorary degrees, 2009 May (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Commencement brochures with insert of winners; University program and Honorary degrees, 2008 May (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Commencement brochures with insert of winners; fan and University program and Honorary degrees, 2007 May (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Arc-CA The Journal of the American Institute of Architects California Council featuring the work of alumnus Craig Hodgetts and Chaired faculty member Stefan Behnisch, 2003 August (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Photos taken by Jim and Sandy Righter of the Class of 1968 reunion in honor of Kent Bloomer held at home of Turner Brooks and Eeva-Liisa Pelkonen, 2008 October 4 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Rudolph Loria Haas Dedication Events, 2008 November 7-8 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Information packet for Robert A.M. Stern (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Program: "Dedicating A New Yale Arts Complex" (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Paul Rudolph Hall, Jeffrey H. Loria Center for the History of Art, and the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library, 2008 November 8 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Market-Driven Prototypes Vol 1, publication of Urbanism Studio 504b second year studio, Spring 2009 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Program for Symposium "Reassessing Rudolph Architecture and Reputation", 2009 January 23-24 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Times Square Palmcards w/cover letter describing the new public sculpture by Gage/Clemenceau Architects – Mark Gage (M Arch 2001) Asst. Prof. of Architecture, 2009 February (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Letter from Peter Corrigan and reply from Dean Robert Stern for copy of Novum Organum Number 8, Spring 1969, 2009 February 9 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Urbanism Studio Mid-term Review" Brochure and draft version for 504b, Spring 2009 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Reunion Souvenir – Class of 1996, 2009 April 9 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "In Memory of Dong Fang Gao" Program from memorial service held at School (2 copies), 2009 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Program Yale Open House for Admitted Students (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Final Review Schedule and Participants (2 copies), 2009 April 27 – 1 May (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Invitation to groundbreaking – First Year Building Project, 2009 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Invitation to celebration of the publication Philip Johnson, The Constancy of Change by Emmanuel Petit, Asst. Prof. of Architecture, 2009 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Invitation post card for Year End Student Exhibit "No Time Like the Present" 22 May to 7 Aug 2009, 2009 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Poster (2)– James Stirling Symposium, 2009 May 9-10 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Symposium program (2) "James Stirling Architecture and Teacher", 2009 May 9-10 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - "Developing Clinton," publication of Arch 905b Intermediate Planning and Development taught by Professor Alexander Garvin, Spring 2009 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - "Thermae/Balnea/Hammam" Morocco studio taught by Demetri Porphyrios and George Knight, Spring 2009 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Course schedule by day and location, Fall 2008, Spring 2009 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Asian Design Culture, edited by William S.W Lim, among the contributors is H. Koom Wee, M.Arch 2003 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Interview: Ada Louise Huxtable by Charlie Rose, "Yale Art and Architecture Building" [commercially-produced], 2009 April 2; optical disc (DVD) (Box 3)
    - Precis from two Advanced Studios – Spring 2008 Corfu Mixed Use Development and Spring 2009 Marrakech, Morocco taught by Demetri Porphyrios and George Knight (Box 4)
    - Linoleum print of Robert Stern by Albert Tidy, M. Arch 1998, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Print by artist Jim Drain titled "Wolf and Lamb" (Box 4)
- "Architectural Internship" brochure from ArchVoices, 2002; Accession 2005-A-008
  - "Architectural Internship" brochure from ArchVoices, 2002 (Box 1)
- Catalogue of "Ant Farm" show, concerning work of Doug Michels (B.Arch, 1967), circa 2004; Accession 2005-A-009
  - Catalogue of Ant Farm show, concerning work of Doug Michels (B.Arch, 1967), circa 2004 (Box 1)
- Issue of American Scholar with article by Christopher Pizzi, Accession 2005-A-010
  - Issue of American Scholar with article by Christopher Pizzi (M.Arch. 2002; Schwarz intern and fellow, 2001), undated (Box 1)
- "Esopus" containing essay by Clayton Eicher (BA, 1985, Architecture, 1989), 2003; Accession 2005-A-011
  - "Esopus" containing essay by Clayton Eicher (BA, 1985, Architecture, 1989), 2003 (Box 1)
- Photocopy of Harvard Design Magazine article about Phyllis Lambert (M.Arch., 1961), Accession 2005-A-012
  - Photocopy of Harvard Design Magazine article about Phyllis Lambert (M.Arch., 1961), undated (Box 1)
- Articles, reminiscences, project list of John Randal McDonald (M.Arch., 1949), Accession 2005-A-014
  - Articles, reminiscences, project list of John Randal McDonald (M.Arch., 1949), undated (Box 1)
- New York World Trade Center Competition, 2003; Accession 2005-A-015
  - New York World Trade Center Competition, book with projects by Yale graduates and faculty., 2003 (Box 1)
- Reminiscences and materials concerning the Yale Department of Architecture and Eero Saarinen, circa 1945; Accession 2005-A-024
  - Reminiscences and materials concerning the Yale Department of Architecture and Eero Saarinen, circa 1945 (Box 1–2)
- "Building 8: Edmond and Corrigan at RMIT", 1996; Accession 2005-A-036
  - "Building 8: Edmond and Corrigan at RMIT", 1996 (Box 1)
- Watercolor painting by Benjamin Thompson, School of Architecture, Class of 1941, Accession 2005-A-045
  - Watercolor painting by Benjamin Thompson, School of Architecture, Class of 1941, Undated (Box 1)
- "l'architecture d'aujourd" featuring the work of Professor Adjunct Kent Bloomer, School of Architecture, 2004; Accession 2005-A-053
  - "l'architecture d'aujourd" featuring the work of Professor Adjunct Kent Bloomer, School of Architecture, 2004 (Box 1)
- Printed materials documenting Architecture, 2003-2004; Accession 2005-A-132
  - "Honors Excellence Occasional Paper Series," honoring Robert Stern, 2003 (Box 1)
  - "Eero Saarinen, Realizing American Utopia", 2004 (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 2004 Summer (Box 1)
- "DZIEDZICTWO" by: Julian E. Kulski (M. Arch 1953), 2004; Accession 2005-A-142
  - "DZIEDZICTWO" by: Julian E. Kulski (M. Arch 1953), 2004 (Box 1)
- Posters created by William S. Huff (BA 1949; M. Arch 1952), 2004; Accession 2006-A-136
- Printed and audiovisual material documenting the School of Architecture, 2005; Accession 2006-A-180
  - Notecards designed by Tim Culvahouse, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Report of the Mississippi Renewal forum, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Copy of Onion article with mention of Yale School of Architecture, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Kazuhiro Ishii's talk on TV Tokyo, 2005; computer files (DVD-Video)
    General note
    Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - Use copy, 1 optical disk (DVD) (Box 2U)
- Published works by Kazuhiro Ishii (M. Arch. 1975), circa 1980-2000; Accession 2006-A-199
  - Published works by Kazuhiro Ishii (M. Arch. 1975), circa 1980-2000 (Box 1)
- Printed and audiovisual material collected by Robert A. M. Stern, Dean, School of Architecture, circa 1974-2005 (inclusive), 2000-2005 (bulk); Accession 2006-A-202
  Scope and Contents
  The accession documents the School of Architecture and its faculty, students, and alumni.
  - Essay on Paul Rudolf from exhibition at New York School of Design (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes from Sidney Sisk regarding Louis Kahn and copy of letter to Edward Rollman (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Works by students, alumni and faculty (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Newsclippings and articles (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pictures (see also Oversize) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Readings for Architecture 716a: Issues in Architecture and Urbanism, taught by Fred Koetter (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sotheby's auction catalog [includes works related to Jean Prouvw (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Audiovisual
    - National Public Radio program about architects Gehry, Hadid, and Garvin, 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - This Old House #2407 featuring the Yale Building Project, 1; videotape (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Being Eisenman, by Robert A. M. Stern on Peter Eisenman teaching at Yale with comments by Stern, Stanley Tigerman, and Clark Gwathmey, computer file (Quicktime movie)
  - Oversize flyer advertising a School of Architecture event with a doctored image of Robert A. M. Stern (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hand-signed prints of Art and Architecture Building by J.C. Hall, #s 5 and 7 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Computer files (Box 4–6)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
- Printed material concerning School of Architecture events and alumni, 2006; Accession 2006-A-216
  - Clippings and announcements, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Tribute to Gerald H. Hines in honor of his 80th birthday, 2005; Accession 2006-A-258
  - Tribute to Gerald H. Hines in honor of his 80th birthday, 2005 (Box 1)
- Printed matter collected by Dean Robert A.M. Stern, 1951-2006; Accession 2007-A-129
  - Class of 1998 newsletter, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits, events, syposia, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Film society, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Material concerning Walter Kaplan Architects (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kumamoto Sewiwa Bunnraku/Puppet Play Complex (Japan), 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Masterworks of Modern American Architecture stamp series (w/ Robert Ventuir's signature), 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  - Newsclippings (cont'd) (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
  - Perspecta 38, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Article concerning Paul Rudolph, Architectural Record, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Urban Age conference (NYU), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Yale Architecture Film Series poster, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Newport News, Virginia project, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Yale Portfolios 2006 Calendar by Arnold Gold (Box 4)
  - Happy hour poster featuring muscle-bound likeness of Dean Stern, 2006 September (Box 4)
  - mad, an architecture design studio, #104/1000 (Box 4)
  - Constructs, 2006 Spring (Box 4)
  - Gwathmey, Siegel, and Associates Architects, School of Architecture Renovation, History of Art Addition, Yale University, DAC Submittal, 2005 November 16 (Box 4)
- Interview of J.C. Calderon and Benny O'Looney [audiorecording], 2001; Accession 2007-A-211
  - Interview with J.C. Calderon and Benny O'Looney on attack on World Trade Center, WBAI 99.5 FM, NYC, 2001 September 16; 1; audiocassette (Box 1)
- Eero Saarinen's drawings and history lesson, 1934; Accession 2008-A-070
  - Eero Saarinen's drawings and history lesson, 1934 (Box 1)
- School of Architecture calendars, 1972-1985; Accession 2008-A-170
  - Calendars, 1972-1985 (Box 1)
- Tee shirt and gifts from Tsinghua University, 1998-2007; Accession 2009-A-055
  - Women in Architecture tee shirt, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Gifts from Tsinghua University (pin, books, bag), 1998-2006 (Box 1)
- Publications and memorabilia, 2007-2008; Accession 2009-A-110
  - Rededication Invitation 30th Anniversary of Architectural Services - David Schwarz (March '74) firm - statement and photos, Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Publicity (Japan) Sunil Bald studio, Spring 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - UDM Workshops- Helsinki University, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Constructs (2 copies), Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photo of Saarinen drawing and note from Donal McLaughlin (M Arch '33) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Walker Art Center announcement of the Saarinen show, Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hawaiian Modern postcard announcing show and reception, Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Memorabilia, 1958-1971; Accession 2007-A-209
  - Architecture Critics Citation on Perspecta, American Institute of Architects, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Section perspective of the Art and Architecture Building, Paul Rudolph, 1958 (Box 2)
- Search [film documenting the General Motors Technical Center, designed by Eero Saarinen], Accession 2011-A-052
  Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
  - Search [film documenting the General Motors Technical Center, designed by Eero Saarinen], Circa 1960 (Box 1)
- Kevin Roche: Architecture as Environment, 2011; Accession 2011-A-058
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
  - Promotional material generated by ASSA ABLOY for the Yale School of Architecture exhibition Kevin Roche: Architecture as Environment, 2011
    Contains one folder with printed information and one DVD produced by ASSA ABLOY.
    - Brochure, flyer and folder, 2011 (Box 1)
    - Photographs (computer files), 2011; 1 (Box 3)
      - Use copy (Box 2)
- Sketchbook and slides by Peter Millard, BArch 1951, Circa 1961-1982; Accession 2011-A-059
  - Sketchbook and slides by Peter Millard, BArch 1951, Circa 1961-1982 (Box 1)
- New York Courthouse competition drawings by Carrere and Hastings, Circa 1913; Accession 2011-A-060 (Box 1)
  - New York Courthouse competition drawings by Carrere and Hastings, Circa 1913